hello my name is green and welcome back
to episode 2 of hermit craft and I have
been extraordinarily busy now haven't
made much progress on the inside of my
base I was hoping to get some of that
done today however I have been busy
mining as you can see by my many broken
pickaxes look at this the fruit of my
strict mining here we are so I mean this
is a lot of resources I may not need to
go strip mining for a long time now
which was my goal precisely so we're
going to take care of this unfortunately
for me my pickaxes are suffering so the
first thing that we need to do is get
ourselves a mending book and fortunately
for me
Ren Dawg has told me that he's got a
villager that I can get them from so
we're gonna go and visit his base
although I'm not entirely sure where
that is sorry what is that scar what
have you made as your starter base it's
a giant eye he said it was a meatball I
definitely I thought it was gonna be
like some sort of wooden eco cube house
thing but no it's a giant snail there's
a giant snail the only you know that's
cool just another day on the hermit
craft server you know one look at that
and I've got to do it I'm sorry I'm
sorry scar I love you and I'm pretty
sure you're going to love this I see you
giant snail and it's just it's just too
perfect I'm so sorry oh no no never
never ever right click just don't keep
an axe in your hand it's the worst
okay well we'll fix that in a minute but
what I want to do here is add a small
but very fashionable Monday mustache
there we go perfect
Scott will love it okay so now we need
to go and find rent I'm sorry I just I
don't know why I felt the need to do
this but I think it's an I think it's
quite an improvement if you ask me okay
okay we need to go and find Ren's base
but genuinely have no idea where anyone
is on this world so I'm gonna quick
be asking so it turns out Ren is on a
little island not this one this one
actually belongs to stress monster who
apparently is also living in the jungle
with the rest of us this is actually a
much more crowded place than I thought
so he lives over yonder and I realized
something that I really should have done
in my last episode in the first episode
which is kind of explain a few things I
kind of forgot so let's head over first
of all one question is what is hermit
craft I know that I would say maybe 95%
of you already know what hermit craft is
but the reality is that there might be
some people that are entirely new to the
entire series and aren't quite sure what
we do here well the answers are simple
we play minecraft a lot of minecraft we
have fun we play with multiple people
from different countries and backgrounds
and play styles and it all comes
together in one gigantic server called
hermit craft and that's as simple as it
gets however this season in particular
we've got a few things that are
different to last time so last time we
were on an island and there were
different districts if you watched
season six
this season is slightly different we
have what you see here a mushroom island
and this is actually going to be the
shopping district for season seven and
eventually this will all be full of
shops as we know our shopping centers to
be and then around the shopping district
or the mushroom island I have no idea
what this is going to be called we then
have loads of different biomes where all
the different Hermits have split up and
settled and made their bases now I'm
looking for a little island just off the
coast of the shopping district where Ren
has told me he lives in a place called
what I don't know whether he called it
this or whether it was just called this
but loser island so this is the this is
the starting place oh must be this
direction
oh no no I've been traveling for like
ten minutes and I didn't bring my
emeralds and I didn't bring my books and
I didn't bring my paper how am I gonna
trade if I don't have anything to trade
with oh here we go again let's go all
the way back I wonder if we can shortcut
through the nether
I haven't actually checked where my
portal is but it must be this direction
I'm pretty sure my portal should be in
this turret that might be my portal I
think that's my portal over there okay
well that makes life quite a lot easier
but not that easy cuz I hear gasp in
fact I see gas come on I can make it I
can make it this is a terrible idea
buddy where'd he go I really want to
make this is gonna save me so much time
and hassle please this is giving me
anxiety right now we made it okay
hopefully this is my portal brilliant
okay so I did actually find some emerald
ore which is brilliant I did have books
with me I just need to make sure I've
gotten a paper to trade so I'm gonna
need quite a few mending books if I'm
honest one two three four five six seven
my fourteen three pick let's see what we
get
17 emeralds might be enough for one book
collect up all of this now let's go and
see if we can get to Ren's house where
we can get our hands on these men
this is definitely the path of death I'm
gonna have to make this a little bit
safer than it currently is no joke do
you mind oh I almost got pushed off
there ha ha that looks like that might
be it doesn't look like a loser island
to me
wonderful oh and he's got a little
mushroom in here okay let's take a look
we don't need doors oops the salmon oh
that might be it I need to know who so
where would Ren keep the villager okay
we're looking for a mending villager in
fact I should have listened for him
because I've just heard him doctor
murdered tittle [\h__\h] PhD oh my goodness
sixty okay I can afford one mending book
is there someone else I can trade with
for emeralds okay it doesn't look like
he has anyone to trade with but I think
I know where I might be able to find
some other villages to be able to trade
with I actually checked the village near
my base as there is one in the spruce
forest but they're all gone no nobody's
home on earth sucked into the dead bush
I'm gonna leave this cursed place
hey it's false hey what's up boss -
anything those those pesky birds take it
all those crops pesky birds ha this
looks like where I'm trying to go cuz I
know for a fact that doc has a bunch of
villages that I can get some emeralds
from but what have they done
oh my goodness they've splitted
- well I mean it is theirs now they
bought it from me fair and square
it's weird seeing a season six build
here whoa
why does he look so broken what's been
going on here well this is a telltale
sign of lots of villagers I don't really
know if I'm supposed to be trading with
his villagers so it's probably best that
we keep a low profile but in exactly
I mean it's no harm there's no harm in
doing it but probably best to just keep
a low profile ah there they are
hello villagers perfect it was a door
right there where are you are you going
well it it's not it's not bedtime I want
to trade thank you go 33 emeralds that
is enough to get me two more mending
books man two and a half hours just to
get some mending books my oh my the
early game is rough my dudes really
really rough
okay now that Ren's firm I think we got
away with that pesky bird okay I'm back
murdered tittle [\h__\h] take my money too
okay we have three men dings that's
smashing smashing job mission
accomplished
three hours of my time let's go back to
the base oh dear and you know what I'm
not even I'm gonna take the nether cuz
this is this is insane whoa do you go
it's it's going it's it's like a torpedo
whoa kid do you mind mr. dolphin you
know take a chill take a chill pill what
that's not how you do that's not how you
swim go back go back into the good and
it says serves you right for being nuts
okay back to the race we go okay silk
touch
mending my goodness that was hard work
I'm gonna save this extra mending book
for later but we got to repair this
because I mean I actually forgot it's
been so long I spent so much time
getting these books that I actually
forgot why I was even getting them in
the first place it's not just to repair
them it's because I want to make use of
all of the strip-mining I've been doing
so let spawning some zombies and get
these repaired scars streaming at ammo
at the moment and he's just discovered
for mustache that I've put on on his
snail which I've just found out it's
called Larry there they are nice stache
something like that well I don't know
certainly wasn't me mm-hmm so now that
we've got our pickaxes up to scratch
what we're going to do is see what we
can get from all of these so the first
thing we're gonna do is get all of the
iron and gold and smelting away okay all
smelting so let's time-lapse getting
ourselves all of this stuff but I think
maybe we should do the diamonds outside
of the time-lapse because that I mean
that's way better with our fortune three
we can see how many we get diamonds
diamonds diamonds diamonds okay there we
go we got a big old stack of diamonds
let's see how many we can get with our
fourteen three there we go it's going
well we're getting a lot I could see all
the diamonds flying off the pillar oh
look at this look at all these diamonds
plus I got a stack here how many did we
get Wow we did well so we just about
doubled our amount of diamonds but I
think it's over so we definitely got a
bit lucky there all right let's
time-lapse the rest of it now that we've
got our diamonds out of the way
[Music]
all collected and organized it looks
pretty decent we got a lot of redstone a
lot of lapis this should do us for a
while but it's not quite enough for a
beacon so my dream of not having to do
any mining is probably not gonna happen
however we can craft ourselves up
diamond gear at last there we go whoa
cover me with diamonds and now we can
enchant this stuff as well what do we
get
blast protection pretty good fire
protection Accra affinity fire
protection thorns I'm braking it's not
the best but it will do we're blue and
shiny once you're over this diamond
hurdle things start to get a little bit
easier so one thing that I want to do
now is I want to do a little bit of work
on my Hobbit base because it's well it's
pretty basic it's really really basic at
the moment I want to get some stuff done
I feel like birch would fit a lot nicer
in here because it's a is that a little
bit bright yeah that's definitely a
better contrast the birch definitely
fits in this season I definitely want to
improve some of my building techniques
in particular I really want to improve
diagonal building diagonal building is
well it's it's not necessarily difficult
it's that it takes a little bit of
getting used to you have to change your
entire perspective of what building in
Minecraft is is meant to look like
because we're very used to working in
these dimensions you know x and y but
when we take into account the diagonals
things do start to get a bit more tricky
so I want to add a little diagonal
window here it's gonna be quite big but
I think it will look quite nice
especially if I decorate it with some
plant egde there we go and then just add
all this grass on the top to make it
look really embedded and then let's take
a step back and see what that looks like
well looks a bit overcrowded maybe I
should have brought it forward a little
bit but on the whole not too shabby
diagonal building is always a bit of a
challenge but I haven't actually spoken
about what my main base is going to look
like
it's not this this is obviously just my
starter base to get get going and then I
need to start working on my main base
and yes this season I'm gonna have a
proper storage system that is really
nice even a small amount of like a
diagonal build can make a huge
difference to the way it feels it's just
because a lot of people don't really use
this technique because it can be a
little tricky to make it look more
natural
but that overall has I think it's added
to it it is a starting to look a bit odd
like there's a small eye and a big eye
but I'm gonna add some more maybe over
here definitely one maybe lower down
over here and this will start to come
together very slowly and hopefully look
quite natural when it's all done so what
I think I'm going to do now is spend a
little time off-camera tidying this
place up and getting it ready for being
a proper base because this is a starter
base mess and I want this to be a
starter base plus alright so I'll be
right back with this hopefully with a
bit more progress behind it you know
I've been working on this for a couple
of days now and I log in and do you hear
this tick tock tick tock now that's not
suspicious at all before I show you what
I've been building I mean you've already
seen it but if we go up here there's a
mysterious grandfather clock and it's
donging every few seconds
it's a magical grandfather clock with a
special surprise oh where is it that
direction no no I'm pretty sure this
isn't the special surprise no get out of
it get out get out of it I think that's
it oh my goodness this it's a annoying
ticking do these buttons do anything oh
my goodness
I assume that scar has done this I mean
well done on the Redstone side of things
but like where the buttons necessary I'm
gonna have to get rid of this because
this ticking in real life this is a
genuine fun fact well
eras in my head this is a genuine fun
fact about me
I really hate clicking clocks if there's
one in the room I won't be able to sleep
so thank you for the clock scar but this
this is far too annoying for me this
might be a slight retaliation for the
zombie prank that we got in with I
appreciate it Scott I really do but at
the same time not for me not for me it's
like he knew okay now we got rid of that
I think we can I can show you what I've
actually been working on so this is like
my secret garden style thing that I got
going on here I'm not entirely sure what
I'm gonna do but I have made a diagonal
entrance Higgs I did say that I wanted
to work on my diagonals so on the inside
here I have made more of a hobbit hole
style thing so you can see I've tried to
get the best sort of circular oval shape
I have made it quite tall just because I
wanted to feel a bit spacious in here
upstairs I've got my nether portal right
there and then I have more importantly
created a proper storage system now it's
not redstone it's not automated it's far
too early for that however check it out
we got your gravel you got your sand
you got Bert bird poop with a bird poop
here we got Greer Knights we got we got
all the things and they're all organized
into their respective chests and that's
I'll tell you what it's actually quite
easy it took me well over an hour to get
this sorted but it's done and I have
been staring at the outside oh wait I
missed a sign hello neighbor
I left you a present in your bedroom
I've already found it can't believe that
was a terrible state I don't know if you
saw that that was a terrible spelling of
neighbor meaning 100% that was scar so
I've been staring at the outside of this
for a really long time and I couldn't
figure out what was wrong with it what
why I why I felt like something wasn't
quite right and I think I figured it out
I think it's to do with the entrance
here it's just a bit lonely I think it
needs a bit
either side goes on on a quote real
hobbit hole the one from the movies
there's a bit there's a bit of wall here
and here so I might try and add that in
now professor beak can you not you are a
noisy boy
noisy boy but you know what I'm gonna
keep this clock I'm gonna keep this I
might add something in here but yeah I'm
definitely keeping the clock it's
definitely gonna take me a few episodes
to get this this base up to scratch
because this obviously this is my
bedroom in here but yeah it's gonna take
me a while to get this all going I was
also reading a few of the comments and
it turns out there's actually quite a
few people living in the jungle not just
me I know of I know scar and I know of
stress but it turns out mumbo and Eskow
are apparently also living in the same
area although I've not seen them so what
we're gonna do is go and hunt down his
scales and mumbos basis and see if we
can see where they are for science for
scientific purposes only another bird
head for my collection
hello pesky bird now I have no idea
where I'm going I'm kind of roaming the
jungle aimlessly for now ah we've hit
the savanna that means we must have
missed it somewhere okay so what I'm
gonna do is I'm gonna kind of search the
jungle like this and then turn and then
keep going until I find someone's base
this jungle ain't big enough for the
four of us although it clearly
it clearly is big enough for the four of
us I'm so lost oh man do you guys see
this one of the most satisfying things
in Minecraft that was a good one is this
a bass doesn't look like a bass
mysterious box of ha mysterious box of
ha wait a minute
gorgeous honeyBun I have a feeling this
might be stress monsters not only could
I not find anyone else's bass I can't
even find my own I am thoroughly
thoroughly lost in this
before the seasons out this jungle has
to go every now and again I find some
signs of life like a bunch of torches
but no basis thoroughly thoroughly lost
another bird head for my collection
pesky bird do you know what I think I
might climb the tallest tree and see if
I can see anything that one over there
I feel like Tarzan this is amazing I
never thought you'd actually be able to
like swing from tree to tree but this is
this is totally possible you know I'm
now convinced that mumbo doesn't even
live in the same jungle now I may not
have got very much out of this but I
have got nearly one of every parrot head
I don't know how many parrots there are
but look at this I got five I'm so lost
you know what I'm gonna just leave the
jungle and figure out going like around
it I'm I think I've been going in
circles for like half an hour
I found neither is cows bass nor mumbos
bass
so y'all guys's comments were all wrong
all wrong
it's me stress and scar in there at the
moment oh okay so I have found his bass
but it's like not really in the jungle
now whose is this is this mumbos or it's
cows this is way east on a hobbit hole
as well this is just like that
spider-man picture you know where
there's there's two spider-man and they
point me eachother
mumble and I have made very similar
bases there can only be one hobbit hole
in this jungle
come kk m ah I don't know what that I
don't know what that means okay I just
went know how to look at their videos
this is 100% mumbo Jumbo's base we found
it but what are we going to do about it
it actually turns out mumbos really
really close to our base our base is
just over yonder I think we need to let
him know this jungle ain't big enough
for two Hobbit holes
there can only be one instead instead of
signing at green I could just do my face
really quick this is the best way to
welcome Mambo without actually doing any
damage to his house we just want him to
know who has the one true hobbit hole in
this jungle welcome to the jungle
everybody is everything behaving as
normal great green isn't or am I am i
behaving as normal Hey look at that
look there could only be one exactly
like my face
as always we could take this one step
further I've only just realized that
Mambo is actually online right now and
he could be back at any moment I had no
idea we gotta be quick we gotta be quick
dudes there we go there could only be
one hobbit hole now let's skedaddle
before Mambo turns up now the reason I
know that this is very close to my base
is because this bamboo forest is the
only one here so it means that my base
must be over here somewhere ah he was
hiding right in plain sight I don't even
think he was hiding I just couldn't find
his base
mission accomplished and now we just
have to try and find this cow where
every scours is there anyone home I've
been to this village so I know that my
base is literally over there oh my
goodness Mambo I'm I am so thankful that
we are neighbors again this is gonna be
a lot of fun Mambo is the best oh my
really really close so still to find is
a scale but I think that's everyone in
our jungle although I would argue that
mumbos not quite in our jungle he's on
the outskirts so we know scar we know
stress and we know mumbos just over
there this is really cool it's so good
having people especially the Hermits
right next to each other because it's
it's so much fun to interact with each
other in this early stage of the game so
what I want to do now is actually
continue working on the base but I in
particular I want to get going on some
of the more redstone e style things
but I'm afraid that is all that I have
got time for today everything in the
early game takes three times longer than
it normally would so I've got to take
things slow a little bit but I think the
progress that we've made is excellent I
think we have discovered a few really
good neighbors and I'm excited for what
comes next so I will see you in episode
3 thank you very much for watching and
good